I believe this is the future of media. To date, most media and social-change strategies have attempted to appeal to mass audiences, but the future is media customized for each person. As real-time measurement of media consumption and automated media production becomes the norm, we will soon be consuming media tailored directly to our cravings using a blend of psychographics, biometrics and AI. It's like personalized medicine based on our DNA. I call it "biomedia." I am currently testing the Limbic Lab in a pilot study with the Norman Lear Center, which looks at the top 50 episodic television shows. But I am grappling with an ethical dilemma. If I design a tool that can be turned into a weapon, should I build it? By open-sourcing the lab to encourage access and inclusivity, I also run the risk of enabling powerful governments and profit-driven companies to appropriate the platform for fake news, marketing or other forms of mass persuasion. For me, therefore, it is critical to make my research as transparent to lay audiences as GMO labels. However, this is not enough. As creative technologists, we have a responsibility not only to reflect upon how present technology shapes our cultural values and social behavior, but also to actively challenge the trajectory of future technology. It is my hope that we make an ethical commitment
Creo que este es el futuro de los medios. Hasta hoy, las estrategias mediáticas y de cambio social han intentado atraer a las masas, pero el futuro es contenido personalizado para cada individuo. A medida que la medición de consumo en tiempo real y la producción automatizada de contenidos parece ser la norma, pronto nos encontraremos consumiendo contenidos hechos a medida, usando una mezcla de psicografía, biométricas e IA. Es como medicina personalizada basada en nuestro ADN. Yo los llamo "biocontenidos". Actualmente estoy probando el Limbic Lab en un estudio piloto con el Norman Lear Center, que tiene acceso a las 50 mejores series de televisión. Pero me veo en un dilema ético. Si diseño una herramienta que se puede convertir en un arma, ¿debería construirla? Al hacerlo en código abierto para fomentar el acceso y la inclusión también corro el riesgo de permitir a poderosos gobiernos y grandes compañías apropiarse de la plataforma para crear noticias falsas, marketing u otras formas de persuasión masiva. Para mí, por lo tanto, es crítico que mi investigación sea lo más transparente posible para la audiencia laica. Sin embargo, esto no es suficiente. Como creadores tecnológicos tenemos la responsabilidad no solo de reflexionar cómo la tecnología actual moldea nuestros valores y comportamiento, sino también cómo desafiar activamente la trayectoria de la tecnología futura. Espero que lleguemos a un compromiso ético
to harvesting the body's intelligence for the creation of authentic and just stories that transform media and technology from harmful weapons into narrative medicine. Thank you. (Applause and cheers)
para aprovechar la inteligencia del cuerpo para crear historias auténticas y justas que transformen los medios y la tecnología de armas peligrosas a medicina narrativa. Gracias. (Aplausos y ovaciones)